## **Evan Sagge**

- Washington DC Metro Area
- evansagge@gmail.com
- +1.813.505.7366

I am a software developer with a focus on web application development, with years of experience in various languages such as Ruby, Java, PHP and C/C++. I specialize in writing web applications, using mostly Ruby on Rails and Rackbased frameworks. I also write code in Javascript/Coffeescript and designing clean and simple HTML5/CSS3-compliant web UIs.

I am heavily influenced with agile development practices, mostly from Scrum, REST-ful web development, test-driven development, and later on behavior-driven development, ensuring that the desired software behavior are properly identified from a practical standpoint and at the same time focusing on delivering simple, efficient, and usable software.

In my free time, I enjoy playing soccer, hiking, running, biking, and traveling to new places.

## **Specializations**

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, MongoDB, Javascript, Coffeescript, jQuery, CSS

# **Professional Experience**

Systems Analyst at **Gannett** (<a href="http://gannett.com">http://gannett.com</a>) - 2012 – Present

- Implemented Salesforce CRM backend requirements using Apex
- Developed Visualforce pages for Salesforce CRM
- Worked on Salesforce CRM integration projects using Ruby on Rails

Associate, Software Development at **iLab Solutions** (<a href="http://ilabsolutions.com">http://ilabsolutions.com</a>) - 2011 – 2012

- Developed and maintained new and existing products and features for in-house web applications using Ruby on Rails and Javascript/Coffeescript
- Ported existing applications from using Prototype to jQuery

Consultant Software Developer at **Deal Grocer** (<a href="http://dealgrocer.com">http://dealgrocer.com</a>)- 2011 - 2012

 Developed additional features for main web application using Cuba (a Rack-based web framework) and Ohm (Redis-based ORM)

Technical Lead (Infinite.ly Project) at **Exist Global** (<a href="http://infinite.ly">http://infinite.ly</a>) - 2011 - 2012

- Developed Ruby on Rails 3 web applications using MongoDB and background processes using Resque and Redis
- Implemented search and indexing capabilities using ElasticSearch
- Designed interfaces to connect with external web-based APIs such as Facebook Graph, Twitter, Google Data, and Flickr APIs to obtain social media data
- Managed remote server infrastructure on Linux instances using Nginx, Uni-corn, Bluepill, Monit and Newrelic

Software Engineer at Exist Global (<a href="http://exist.com">http://exist.com</a>) - 2008 – 2011

- Implemented and maintained web and mobile applications for various cli-ents, most of which are developed using Ruby on Rails technologies.
- Developed new features and enhanced existing functionalities for the TotSpot social networking web site using Facebook's OpenStream API and Twitter's OAuth API
- Developed a web-based photo-management application using Ruby on Rails 2.3.x and Facebook REST API
- Developed iPhone application to render photos as cartoonized images

Web Developer at **Syndeo Media** (<a href="http://syndeomedia.com">http://syndeomedia.com</a>) - 2007 - 2008

 Implemented new features and enhanced existing functionalities for client-based projects using Ruby on Rails

Software Developer at Solegy - 2006 - 2007

 Developed and maintained new and existing software solutions using a mix of C++, Java (J2SE and J2EE) and Ruby coding languages

Software Design Engineer at **Blue Chip Designs** (<a href="http://bcdph.com">http://bcdph.com</a>) - 2005 - 2006

Developed software solutions (drivers, firmware, desktop applications)
for thermal printer devices, point-of-sales systems using C/C++ and OLE,
Ac-tiveX, COM, MFC frameworks

#### **Freelance Work**

Training Payback (http://trainingpayback.com) - 2007 to 2008

 Developed new features and enhance existing functionalities using Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL

Babyland (<a href="http://babyland.com.ph">http://babyland.com.ph</a>) - 2006

 Designed and developed the original website using CakePHP and MySQL

Schema Konsult (http://schemakonsult.com) - 2007

Designed and developed the website using PHP and MySQL

# **Open Source Projects**

Mongoid-RSpec (<a href="https://github.com/evansagge/mongoid-rspec">https://github.com/evansagge/mongoid-rspec</a>)

- RSpec plugin to provide matchers for the Mongoid ORM
- primary developer

### Flickr-OAuth (<a href="https://github.com/evansagge/flickr\_oauth">https://github.com/evansagge/flickr\_oauth</a>)

- simple Ruby library for connecting to the Flickr API
- primary developer

#### Numeric Array (https://github.com/evansagge/numeric\_array)

- Ruby library extending Array objects to provide methods for mathematical and statistical calculations
- primary developer

#### CakePHP (http://cakephp.org)

- PHP-based web development framework, similar to Ruby on Rails for Ruby
- contributor from 2005-2007

## **Skills & Expertise**

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, ElasticSearch, Redis, HAML, Slim, Javascript, Coffeescript, Prototype, jQuery, CSS, SASS, Compass, Nginx, Passenger, Unicorn, Monit, Bluepill, Rack, Cuba, Salesforce CRM, Apex, Visualforce Pages

### **Education**

- Ateneo de Manila University, Philippines B.S. Computer Engineering, 2000 - 2005
- Ateneo de Manila University, Philippines B.S. Physics, 2000 2004